(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-14T17:59:52.603398",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
2018年から5年間
For five years since 2018,
通り過ぎてきた たくさんの夜
we've passed through so many nights.
長かったような 短かったような
They felt both so long and so short,
何度でも繰り返したいような 繰り返し…たい…
that I'd want to repeat them over and over...
君はこのループから抜け出したいの？
Do you want to escape from this loop?
聴こえますか 聴こえますか
Can you hear me? Can you hear me?
夜光通信
Nightlight transmission.
ハロー ハロー 聴こえますか
Hello, hello, can you hear me?
そっちは何年？
What year is it on your end?
正しく分かり合う手段はひとつじゃないさ
The right way to understand each other isn't just one.
漂う時間は何処へ行くのか
Where is this drifting time heading?
さよならはいつ誰が決めるの
Who decides when it's time to say goodbye?
その手に触れようと願ってる 本当さ
I'm wishing just to touch your hand, truly.
永遠の夜光 君に歌う
An eternal nightlight, I sing to you.
世界中が君に意地悪でも
Even if the whole world is mean to you,
思い出して 覚えていて
remember it, keep it in mind—
まぶたの裏 ずっとまた会えるからね
behind your eyelids, we'll surely meet again.
穏やかに 健やかに
Calmly, soundly.
君だって 私だって 消えるのは
Whether it's you or me, what fades away
言葉だけ ふんわり君を抱きしめてあげるからね 泣かないで
is just words. I'll gently hold you close, so don't cry.
延々と続く 今日は
Today that goes on and on eternally
誓言のようで 突然の別れまでも
feels like a vow, even unto a sudden parting.
あいも変わらず
Unchanging as always,
上ばかり見ておかしくなる
looking only upward makes me feel strange,
やる気曇っていく
and my motivation clouds over.
責任掛けっせ
Shifting responsibilities,
明日に背を向け
turning my back on tomorrow,
色褪せた過去とやり合ってんだ
I'm dealing with a faded past.
抑え付けるほどかさ増ししていく劣等感 その他諸々
The inferiority complex piles up the more I hold it back, and everything else.
溺れる前に夜を染め上げなくちゃ
I've got to paint the night before I drown.
Flap...Phew!
Flap... Phew!
敵じゃないポーズ決め込んで
Striking a pose like I'm not an enemy,
不満さんポッケ詰め込んで
stuffing my pockets with grievances.
叩き割ったら増える ひたづまひたつ
Smash it open and it multiplies, one by one,
もう飲み込めないくらい
to the point I can't swallow it anymore.
ほらくれてやるよ 食えよ全部
Here, I'll give it to you, eat it all up,
ちゃんと噛んで味わいながら
chewing it properly and savoring the taste.
感想聞いてみてもいいですか
May I ask for your thoughts?
僕ら灰を背負ったままでナイトループだ そう壊れるまで
We're on a night loop carrying ashes, until we break down.
嘘をぎゅっとしたサイコールールじゃ もう縛れないよ
In a psycho rule gripping tight lies, we can't be bound anymore.
正解すら間違えてるんだ
Even the correct answers are mistaken.
そうだろう誰しも彼しも馬鹿みたい
That's right, everyone looks like a fool.
イタイの飛んでいけナイトループだ そう上がれるまで
Let the pain fly away on this night loop, until we can rise up.
やいやいどうしようもないから もう騙さないで
Hey now, there's nothing we can do, so don't deceive me anymore.
あと少しで絶望と希望の境界線 背伸びすれば届きそうな称賛
Just a bit more to the boundary line of despair and hope, praise seemingly in reach if I stand on tiptoe.
うだうだ脱線したい
Rambling and wanting to derail,
うーわって声漏らしちゃって目逸らしちゃって
letting out sighs of "whoa," looking away,
凹み散らすまでがワンセット やる気アンデッド
getting utterly depressed is all part of the set, motivation undead.
毎日がニューな己のバースデイ
Every day is my new personal birthday.
諦めても諦めなくても僕を置いて進んでく時間
Whether I give up or not, time marches on leaving me behind.
残された呼吸を使い果たせば
If we use up the remaining breath,
抱きとめた記憶さえ灰へと散る
even the memories we held onto scatter into ashes.
鼓動とは呪いだと気づきながら
Realizing that a heartbeat is a curse,
参列者は笑い行く 虚ろな棺
the mourners walk away laughing by an empty coffin.
その叫びもやがて過去に溶ける
That cry too will soon melt into the past,
暗室の花だけを道連れに
taking only the flower of the dark room as a companion.
嫌だよ終わるために生まれた悲劇など
I hate it, tragedies born just to end.
息を止めて そのままで 命よ銀に光れ
Stop your breath, stay just as you are, shine in silver, O life!
果たなき夢が いつまでも 続きますように
May this endless dream continue forevermore.
消えたくないよ 消えないで ただそれだけを祈った
I don't want to fade away, don't disappear, I prayed for just that.
最後の最後の幸せ 誰にも誰にも奪わせない 離さない
The very last happiness—I won't let anyone, anyone take it away, I won't let go.
造られた世界は どちらだろうか
Which one is this created world?
目を背け死神に飼われたのは
Looking away and being kept by the reaper,
揺れる火の鮮やかさを持て余す頃
around the time we have more than enough of the flickering flame's brilliance,
白蠟は泣き続ける その結末を
the white wax continues to cry over that ending.
思い出せ 朝を迎えるのはあと何日だろう
Remember, how many days until we welcome the morning?
許された時間はあと何分だろう
How many minutes of granted time do we have left?
この心が満たされるのはあと何秒だろう
How many seconds until this heart is fulfilled?
怖いよ届かずに朽ちてゆくその日が
I'm scared of the day it rots away without reaching anyone.
息を止めて そのままで 命よ銀に光れ
Stop your breath, stay just as you are, shine in silver, O life!
優しい唄が いつまでも 響きますように
May this gentle song echo on forevermore.
悲しみもいつか去るのならいつまでは繰り返そう
If sadness will eventually leave, let's repeat it until when.
こんなにこんなにささやかだ 最後の最後の願いごと
So simple, so humble, this very last wish of mine.
安らかなる 日々だけが 続けばよかった
I wish only peaceful days could go on.
それを守るだけの力 が在ればよかった
I wish I had the strength to protect them.
静かな夕凪をずっと 見ていたかった
I wanted to keep watching the quiet evening calm.
それを守るだけの力 が在ればよかった
I wish I had the strength to protect them.
安らかなる 日々だけが 続けばよかった
I wish only peaceful days could go on.
それを守るだけの力 が在ればよかった
I wish I had the strength to protect them.
静かな夕凪をずっと 見ていたかった
I wanted to keep watching the quiet evening calm.
それを守るだけの力 が在ればよかった
I wish I had the strength to protect them.
安らかなる 日々だけが 続けばよかった
I wish only peaceful days could go on.
それを守るだけの力 が在ればよかった
I wish I had the strength to protect them.
静かな夕凪をずっと 見ていたかった
I wanted to keep watching the quiet evening calm.
全てを捧げても
Even if I give up everything.
息を止めて そのままで 命よ銀に光れ
Stop your breath, stay just as you are, shine in silver, O life!
果たなき夢が いつまでも 続きますように
May this endless dream continue forevermore.
消えたくないよ 消えないで ただそれだけを祈った
I don't want to fade away, don't disappear, I prayed for just that.
最後の最後の幸せ それでもそれでも触れるなら許さない
The very last happiness—even so, if you touch it, I won't forgive you.
安らかなる 日々だけが 続けばよかった
I wish only peaceful days could go on.
それを守るだけの力 が在ればよかった
I wish I had the strength to protect them.
静かな夕凪をずっと 見ていたかった
I wanted to keep watching the quiet evening calm.
それを守るだけの力 が在ればよかった
I wish I had the strength to protect them.
安らかな日々だけが続けばよかった
If only peaceful days could go on forever,
それを守るだけの力が在ればよかった
if only I had the power to protect them.
静かな夕凪をずっと見ていたかった
I wanted to keep watching the quiet calm.
安らかな日々だけが続けばよかった
If only peaceful days could go on forever,
それを守るだけの力が在ればよかった
if only I had the power to protect them.
すべてを捧げても
Even if I sacrifice everything,
息を止めて そのままで
holding my breath, just as I am,
命を銀に光らせ
making my life shine silver,
果てなき夢が いつまでも続きますように
may my endless dream continue forever...
消えたくないよ 消えないで ただそれだけを祈った
I don't want it to fade, please don't fade away—that was all I prayed for.
最後の 最後の 幸せ
My final, final happiness...
それでも それでも 触れるなら 許さない
Even so, even so, if you reach out, I won't forgive you.
雨、やまないな…
The rain won't stop...
みおちゃーん！
Mio-chan!
あやめ！ こんなとこで何してんの？
Ayame! What are you doing in a place like this?
あやめこそ こんなとこで会うなんて奇遇だね
Of all places, running into you here, Ayame—what a coincidence.
雨、やまないね。
The rain really won't stop.
そうだね…
Yeah, it won't...
雨だけど あやめに会えて嬉しいな
Even though it's raining, I'm so glad I got to see you, Ayame.
あやめ、なんかあった？
Ayame, did something happen?
なんもないよ！ うそうそ！ うちもあやめに会えて嬉しいよ
Nothin' at all! Just kidding! I'm super glad I got to see Ayame too!
もうちょっとお話ししたいな。 うん！
I want to talk a bit more. Yeah!
ああ全然できてないなぁ…
Ah, I'm still not doing very well at all...
漏らす吐息、溜息
Letting out sighs, heavy sighs,
雨音響いていく 午前0時
as the sound of rain echoes at midnight.
明けない夜願っている 少しだけこのままで
Praying for a night that never ends, wishing to stay like this just a little longer.
ココロ、夜と雨の中
My heart is lost in the night and the rain.
揺れる想い まだ整理途中
My wavering feelings are still in the middle of being sorted out.
流れる時間の中
Amidst the flowing passage of time,
明日晴れたらいいな
I hope tomorrow will be clear and sunny.
そんなささやかな 願いごとカタチにして集めよう
Let's gather such small wishes and shape them into reality.
夜照らすムーンライト 空を泳ぐ
Moonlight illuminating the night, swimming through the sky.
顔上げて前へ 踏み出していこう
Lift your head up and take a step forward into the future.
夜と雨の先 出口はまだ
Beyond the night and the rain, the exit is still far away.
ああ全然変わらないな 漏れる軽い微笑み
Ah, nothing has changed at all, as a faint smile slips out.
液晶見つめる 午前3時
Staring at the screen at 3 a.m.
楽しいコト 悲しいコト ひとつに丸めちゃって
Fun things, sad things, rolling them all up into one ball
夜の中に置いておくの
and leaving them behind in the night.
「頑張ろう」とか 「できるよ」とか
Words like \"Do your best\" or \"You can do it\"—
無責任な言葉たち 逆に辛くなるから
those irresponsible words only end up hurting more,
真っ直ぐに進みたいよ
so I just want to walk straight ahead.
流れる時間の中
Amidst the flowing passage of time,
駆けだす
I start running.
明日会えたらどんな顔するかな
What kind of face will I make if I see you tomorrow?
朝日みたいな笑顔で迎えて
Greeting you with a smile like the morning sun,
夜照らすムーンライト 街を眺む
moonlight illuminating the night, gazing out at the town.
悩みすらすっ飛ぶ 見透かすように
As if seeing right through all my worries,
降りやまない雨
the rain keeps falling without stopping.
降り止まないまま
Still not stopping...
夜明けは まだ
Dawn is still far away.
Lalala...
窓に映る景色 雨は宝石で
The scenery in the window, rain like jewels,
夜空は 黒いドレスのようにきらめいて
the night sky glitters like a black dress,
私を照らす
illuminating me.
夜は明けないから
The night will not end,
まだ この夜が好きだから
so I still love this night.
夜と雨に 包まれていく ああ
Enveloped by the night and rain, ah...
明日晴れたらいいな そんなささやかな
"I hope tomorrow is clear"—such a small
願いごとカタチにして 集めよう
wish turned into shape, let's gather them.
夜照らすムーンライト 空を泳ぐ
Moonlight illuminating the night, swimming through the sky,
顔上げて前へ 踏み出していこう
lift your face forward and take a step out.
君と一緒なら 超えたいから
If I'm with you, I want to overcome it,
夢みたいに 言葉でも
like a dream, even in words.
夜と雨の先 明けたら、ほら
Beyond the night and rain, when dawn breaks, look...
あたたかい雪が降る
Warm snow falls
不思議な場所
in this mysterious place.
デジャヴみたい
Like déjà vu,
真っ白な夜
a pure white night
ぽつりと 咲いている
blooming quietly alone,
赤いほほの 私見つけて
find me with my red cheeks.
つかれたね かなしいね もうやめたいね
We're tired, we're sad, we want to stop,
でもふりしぼって 私へとたどりついてくれて ありがとう
but thank you for gathering your strength and reaching me.
あなたを待っていたの ずっとここで
I was waiting for you, right here all along.
世界が目覚めても そばにいさせて
Even if the world wakes up, let me stay by your side.
あなたのために咲くよ ずっとここで
I will bloom for you, right here all along.
春に追いつくされても 覚えていて
Even if spring catches up to us, please remember.
いつの間にか
Before I knew it,
泣き方も忘れてた
I had even forgotten how to cry.
空っぽの箱
An empty box,
ひとりきりだった
all alone.
さみしくて 折れそうで 傷ついても 愛してしまうの
Lonely, ready to break, even when hurt, I end up loving you.
あきらめず 探していてくれて ありがとう
Thank you for searching for me without giving up.
あなたを待っていたの ずっとここで
I was waiting for you, right here all along.
春に追いつくされても 覚えていて
Even if spring catches up to us, please remember.
ひらひら 舞い降りる雪が
The snow fluttering down
やさしいね
is so gentle.
いまこの瞬間 しあわせと名づけさせて
Let me name this very moment "happiness."
あなたのために咲くよ ずっとここで
I will bloom for you, right here all along.
春に追いつくされても 覚えていて
Even if spring catches up to us, please remember.
君に出会うことができて、本当によかった。
I'm so glad I was able to meet you.
これからも、君の居場所になれるように、いつでも、ふっと思い出してもらえるように、
From now on, so I can be your safe place, so you can fondly remember me anytime...
このライブで、咲き続けるからね！
I'll keep blooming in this live!
ねぇ、今日が何の日か覚えてる？
Hey, do you remember what day today is?
そう、うちがホロライブで活動を始めて、5年経ったんだよ！
That's right, it's been 5 years since I started streaming in Hololive!
うーん、いろんなことがあったけど、楽しかったなって思うことの方が多かったかな。
Hmm, a lot has happened, but I feel like there were way more fun moments.
本当だよ！君にも出会うことができたしね。
It's true! I was able to meet you, too.
え、もう行っちゃうの？
Eh, are you leaving already?
そっか、君にも色々あるよね。でも大丈夫、またきっと会えるよ。
I see, you've got a lot going on too. But it's okay, we'll definitely meet again.
またね！
See you!
幽霊東京
[Song: Ghost Tokyo]
燦然と輝く街の灯り
The dazzling lights of the city shine brightly
対照的な僕を見下ろす
Looking down at my contrasting self
あのビルの間を抜けて 色付き出したネオンと混ざって
Slipping between those buildings, mixing with the glowing neon
僕の時間とこの世界をトレード 夜に沈む
Trading my time and this world, sinking into the night
終電で家路を辿る僕の 目に映るガラス窓に居たのは
Tracing my way home on the last train, what was in the glass window
夢見た自分じゃなくて
Wasn't the me I dreamed of being,
今にも泣き出してしまいそうな 暗闇の中独り唯迷っている 哀しい人
A sad person wandering alone in the darkness, about to burst into tears at any moment
大丈夫、いつか大丈夫になるなんて想う日々をいくつ重ねた
How many days have I spent thinking "It'll be alright someday"?
今日だってひとり東京の景色に透ける僕は幽霊みたいだ
Even today, transparent in the scenery of Tokyo all alone, I look just like a ghost.
失うことに慣れていく中で 忘れてしまったあの願いさえも
As I get used to losing things, even that wish I had forgotten
思い出した時に 涙が落ちたのは
When I remembered it, the tears that fell
この街がただ 余りにも眩しいから
Were simply because this city is far too dazzling.
散々だって笑いながら嘆く退屈な日々の中 あの日の想いがフラッシュバック
Laughing and lamenting that it's a mess, the feelings of that day flash back
気付けば朝まで開くロジック 僕の言葉を音に乗せて何度でも
Before I knew it, opening logic until morning, putting my words into sound over and over.
失うことに慣れていく中で 忘れてしまったあの日子でさえも
As I get used to losing things, even those days that I forgot,
それでもまだ先へ なんて思えるのは 君がいるから
Still heading further ahead — the reason I can think that way is because you are here.
ねぇ こんな寂しい街で ねぇ
Hey, in such a lonely city, hey...
燦然と輝く街の灯り
The dazzling lights of the city shine brightly
対照的な僕を見下ろす
Looking down at my contrasting self
あのビルの先 手を伸ばして あの日夢見た景色をなぞって
Reaching out my hand beyond those buildings, tracing the scenery I dreamed of that day
僕の時間とこの世界をトレード 明日を呼ぶ
Trading my time and this world, calling for tomorrow.
失うことに慣れていく中で 失わずにいた大事な想いを
As I get used to losing things, embracing those precious feelings I didn't lose,
抱きしめたらふいに 涙が落ちたのは
When I hugged them, suddenly the tears that fell,
この街でまだ 生きていたいと思うから 君もそうでしょう
Because I still want to live in this city — you think so too, right?
真夜中 流れれてく
Flowing through the midnight,
ビルをなぞって 消える
tracing the buildings and disappearing.
どこへゆくの？
Where are you heading?
変わってゆくこと 気づいて 立ちどまった
I noticed things changing and stopped in my tracks.
曖昧で不確かなもの 終わりあることだから
Because ambiguous and uncertain things eventually come to an end—
私は此処にある 君といる時間の中で 呼吸をするんでしょう
I am right here, breathing within the time spent with you.
変わらないで、と 終わらないで、と 今日も 夜明けを噛む
Saying \"don't change,\" saying \"don't ever end,\" I bite into the dawn once again today.
「輝いていたい」 こんな世界で憂う私を どうか寝かさないで
\"I want to shine.\" Please don't let me sleep, me who grieves in a world like this.
君の隣で溶けて消えるまで 生きて
Live, until I melt and fade away right beside you.
揺らいだ切なさは いつかの朝に似てる
This wavering sorrow resembles a certain morning.
「ひとりじゃない」 眩さの中 確かに触れた
\"I'm not alone\"—I touched it for sure within the brilliance.
心の片隅 君の瞳に映る私を 焼き付けて
Burn into me the image of myself reflected in your eyes, in the corner of my heart.
その手で抱きしめて きっと誰よりも強く輝けるでしょう
Embrace me in your hands; I'm sure I can shine brighter than anyone.
変わりゆくもの 終わりゆくもの ひとつ またたくように
Things that change, things that end—like a single twinkling light.
「確かめていたい」 霞む世界に歌う私を どうか忘れないで
\"I want to be sure\"—please don't forget me, singing in a hazy world.
君の記憶の底へ 淡く甘く 滲んで ひとつになって ただようだけ
Into the depths of your memory, softly and sweetly bleeding, becoming one, just drifting along.
泣き出しそうな 夜の隙間を縫って
Sewing through the gaps of a night that looks ready to cry,
私は往く 夜明けのメロウ 君の隣で溶けて消えるまで 生きて
I walk on, the melody of dawn. Live, until I melt and vanish by your side.
待ってたよ、
You've been waiting, haven't you?
たくさん。
A lot.
みおさ、ファーストアルバムが出せるってなったとき、相当嬉しかったんだよ。
When it was decided that I could release my first album, Mio was so, so happy.
歌うことは大好きだったけど、自信が正直なかったからさ、
I always loved singing, but honestly I didn't have much confidence, so...
もう、これ以上うまく歌えることはないだろうなって、勝手に思っちゃっててさ。
I kind of just assumed, \"Well, I probably won't ever be able to sing any better than this.\"
でもね、君が待っててくれたから、
But you know, because you waited for me,
うまくならないって思ってたのに、なんか成長したなって思うんだよね。
even though I thought I wouldn't get any better, somehow I feel like I've grown.
より一層歌が好きになれたんだ。
I've come to love singing even more than before.
気づかせてくれたのは、君だよ。
And the one who made me realize that is you.
何処まで往こうか ネイビな夜空に
How far shall I go into the navy night sky?
映る昨日の自分 夢見がちだった
The past self reflected there was so prone to dreaming.
ベイビーフェイスに
To your baby face,
サヨナラ？
goodbye?
見たくないモノ照らすハイビームに
In the high beams illuminating what I don't want to see,
走る焦燥感 跳ね除けて前へ往けば
a rushing impatience—if I brush it aside and press forward,
信号は皆 色を無くし消えた
all the traffic lights lost their colors and vanished.
確かめたい
I want to confirm
この道が繋ぐ場所を
where this road leads.
深く、深く紺になる
Deeply, deeply turning deep indigo.
夜を往ける この加速度
This acceleration traversing the night,
光さえ超えてゆける程に
to the extent that I can surpass even light itself.
強く、強く踏み込んで僕は駆ける ただ真っ直ぐに
Stepping down fiercely, fiercely, I run straight ahead.
譲れない想いを抱いて
Holding onto unyielding feelings.
標識だらけの街を抜け出して
Breaking out of the signpost-filled town,
未来を探してた
I was searching for the future.
常識も何も 全部 雑多と化してた
Common sense and everything else had turned into clutter.
何処まで往けるの なんて聞き飽いた台詞吐いて
Uttering that tired line, "How far can you go?"
曇った窓ガラスに書いた本音 すぐに指で消した
The true feelings written on the foggy windowpane, I erased with my finger instantly.
臆病でも 揺るぎない軌跡
Even if cowardly, an unshakable trace,
確かな願いを 胸に 遥か遠く
a certain wish in my chest, far, far away.
錆び付くように軋んでも この真っ暗を灯し進む
Even if creaking as if rusting, I push forward lighting up this pitch blackness.
ただ一つ 答えを追いかけて
Chasing after just one answer.
脆くてもいい この腕で掴む為に手を伸ばすよ
Even if frail, I reach out my hands to grasp it with these arms.
打ち鳴らす鼓動の限り
To the limit of my beating heart.
何度 この道で迷って 見失って どこへ往くの
How many times, getting lost on this road, losing sight, where am I going?
目指す場所も その意味も 一つしか無いのに 曇った視界は
Even though there's only one destination and one meaning, my clouded vision
夜に溶けて もう一度 ひらけてゆく
melts into the night and opens up once again.
視線の先 僕を連れて往くよ きっと
Ahead of my gaze, it will surely lead me away.
深く、深く紺になる
Deeply, deeply turning deep indigo,
息を吸って 今 加速を
taking a breath, now accelerating.
傷付く程に強くなると 確かな色 動き出す
As I grow stronger the more I get hurt, true colors begin to move.
纏ってゆく その身体で 鮮やかな夜空の果てへ 忘れないように
Clothed in that body, toward the edge of the vibrant night sky, so I won't forget.
深く、深く紺になれ 今を生きる この加速度 光だって超えてゆける場所へ
Deeply, deeply become deep indigo, this acceleration living in the present, to a place where I can surpass even light.
強く、強く踏み込んで僕は駆ける ただ真っ直ぐに
Stepping down fiercely, fiercely, I run straight ahead.
譲れない想いを抱いて
Holding onto unyielding feelings.
止まらないで 走り続く意味を知るから
Don't stop, because I know the meaning of continuing to run.
わくわくエブリデイ
[Title: Wakuwaku Everyday]
心地よい晴れ空
A pleasant, clear sky,
今日は何をして遊ぼうか
what should we play today?
いつまでも変わらない 雲を追いかけてみようか
Shall we chase the clouds that never change?
はしゃぎ回って 疲れて
Running around and getting tired,
お腹もすいて 寝転んで
getting hungry and lying down.
明日はもっといい日になりそう 一緒だよ
Tomorrow looks like it'll be an even better day, we're together!
いつもキラキラ毎日止まらないでしょ
Every day sparkles brightly and never stops, right?
やりたいこと全部遊び尽くしても
Even if we play out everything we want to do,
Even if we play and exhaust everything we want to do,
今はまだ知らないこと沢山あるけど
There are still so many things we don't know yet,
君と君と手を取って
Taking each other's hands,
ずっと笑えるといいよね
I hope we can keep smiling forever.
朝まで語り込んで眠くなる日もあったよね
There were days we talked until morning and got sleepy,
些細な悩みさえも笑いに変えてくれたよね
And turned even the smallest worries into laughter.
たまに怒ってうつむいて 励まし合って乗り越えて
Sometimes getting angry and looking down, encouraging each other—
一人じゃできないことでも二人なら
Even things we couldn't do alone, together—
ほらね？ワクワクすること止まらないでしょ
See? The excitement just won't stop, right?
やりたいこと叶える力があるよ
We have the power to make our dreams come true.
そうでしょう？ときめくココロに色づく毎日
Right? Every day colors our throbbing hearts.
君と君と手を取って「今」を重ね続けてこう
Taking each other's hands, let's keep stacking up 'now'.
笑顔の帰り道も
On the way home full of smiles too,
何年経っても 君となら ずっと…
No matter how many years pass, with you, forever...
いつまでだって続くんだ どこまでだって行けそうだ
It will go on forever, we feel like we can go anywhere.
友達なんて言葉じゃまだ足りないよ
Words like 'friends' are still not enough.
いつもそばで支えてくれてありがとう
Thank you for always supporting me by my side.
一緒に笑い合ってくれてありがとう
Thank you for sharing laughs together with me.
今はまだ知らないこと沢山あるけど
There are still so many things we don't know yet,
君と君と手を取って 転んで泣きそうな時も 君と君と明日も
Taking each other's hands, even when we stumble and might cry, with you tomorrow too—
ずっと笑えるといいよね
I hope we can keep smiling forever.
これからもね よろしくどうぞ
Here's to looking forward to our future together!
皆さんお待ちかね！活動5周年記念フルセット、記念グッズはこちらとなっております！
Everyone, you've been waiting for it! The 5th anniversary full set and commemorative goods are right here!
はい、こんな感じのフルセットですね。いやあ泉パパのイラストが今回も光っております。
Yes, it's a full set like this. Oh, Izumi-papa's illustrations are shining bright this time too.
では一個ずつグッズを紹介させてもらいます！まずは泉パパ描き下ろしのパブミラー！
Now let's introduce the goods one by one! First, the pub mirror illustrated by Izumi-papa!
パブミラーって一体なんだって思ってる人も結構多いと思うんですけど、パブミラーは、イラストの背景が鏡になってて高級感があって特別な感じのインテリアみたいな感じなのかな？
I think quite a few people might be wondering what a pub mirror actually is, but the background of the illustration is a mirror, giving it a luxurious, special kind of interior feel.
で、今回アクリルスタンドとはまた別に高級感、特別感を出したくてパブミラーを出してみました！皆さんのご自宅に飾ってみてください！
And this time, separate from the acrylic stand, I wanted to bring out that luxurious and special feeling, so I decided to release a pub mirror! Please display it in your homes!
そしてお次が、ミオシャとおでかけコインケース！
And next, Mio-sha's Outing Coin Case!
こちらはみんながイベントに行く時に、よくコインを使うんじゃないかと思って、そのコインを出し入れするためだけのコインケースがあったら便利なんじゃないかなと思い作ってみました！このコインケースと一緒にイベントに行ってくれたらうちはとっても嬉しいなー！
I thought people often use coins when going to events, so I made this coin case just for taking coins in and out! I'd be so happy if you went to events with this coin case!
はい、ではお次、ミオシャ思い出フォトフレーム！
Yes, next up, the Mio-sha Memories Photo Frame!
こちらはうちがいつも特典でつけてるポストカードを入れるのにちょうどいい感じのフォトフレームを作ってみました！またね、この鹿テナ先生の描き下ろしなんですけどコインケースもね描き下ろししていただいたんですが、とっても可愛いですね！
I made this photo frame sized just right for putting in the postcards I always give as bonuses! Also, this is illustrated by Shikaten-sensei—the coin case was also drawn by them, and it's so cute!
ぜひぜひこちらのの中にポストカードを飾ってお家で眺めてみてくださいね！
Please definitely display your postcards inside this and admire them at home!
はい、そして最後が、ミオファの森の住民カード！
Yes, and finally, the Miofa Forest Resident Card!
こちらはですね、ミオファの森の住民のみんなが、ミオファの森内での身分証明書に使えるように作ってみました！何言ってるのか
This is something I made so that all residents of Miofa Forest can use it as an ID within Miofa Forest! What am I saying...
よくわかんないと思うけどね、
You probably don't get it yet, but
はい、ちなみにシリアル番号は、えっと、それぞれ入っているんですけれども、
Right, by the way, each one has a serial number,
えーシリアル番号が全員が違うので、世界に1つだけ、1枚だけのカードとなっておりますので、ぜひミオファの皆はゲットしてみてください。
but since every serial number is different, it's a one-of-a-kind card in the world, so Miofa, please be sure to get yours.
そして、最後にこのグッズのフルセットを買ってもらうと、特典が2つあります！
And finally, if you buy the full set of these goods, there are two special bonuses!
大神ミオ直筆サイン＆箔押し複製メッセージ入りポストカード、泉見パパ描き下ろしのポストカード！イェイ！長ーい！長ーい！
A postcard with Mio's handwritten signature and foil-stamped message, and one by Izumi-papa! Yay! So long!
えーと、うちが、えー直筆のサインを入れて、さらに箔押しの、箔押しじゃない、箔押しのメッセージが入ったポストカードとなっておりまーす。
Um, with my handwritten signature and a foil-stamped message added to it.
泉見パパのイラストで、さっきのパブミラーのイラストなんだけど、ちょっと差分で表情が違ったりするので、ぜひぜひこちらも手に入れてください。
It's Izumi-papa's illustration—same as the pub mirror, but with a slightly different expression, so please get this too!
そして、お次が、えー特典2つ目！特典ボイス、えー5周年のあと君と一緒に！というテーマでシチュエーションボイスを撮らせていただきましたー！
And next, the second bonus! A bonus voice situation recorded with the theme "Together with you after 5 years"!
もうちょっといつもね、あのボイス取るの少し恥ずかしいんだけれども、5年間一緒に過ごしてくれたみんなに感謝の気持ちを込めて、えーシチュエーションボイス台本から考えたので、ぜひぜひちょっと恥ずかしいですが聞いてくださーい！
It's a bit embarrassing for me to record voice packs, but with gratitude to everyone who spent 5 years with me, I wrote the script myself, so please listen!
はあー。
*sigh*
さて、グッズ告知も終わったね。
Now then, the goods announcement is done.
けど、なんかもの足りないな。
But, something feels a bit lacking.
君もなんか短いなって思ってない？
Don't you think it feels a bit short too?
ああ、そっか！もの足りないならもう1回5年目いっとく？
Ah, I see! If it's lacking, shall we go through year 5 once more?
ここだけの話、ライブのタイトルのナイトループってあるじゃん？あれって気づいてたかもしれないけど、曲名なんだよね。
Just between us, you know the live title "Night Loop"? You might have noticed, but that's the song title.
この夢のようなライブが終わったあとに、なんとMVも公開されちゃいます！
After this dream-like live concert ends, amazingly, the MV will also be released!
じゃあ心の準備はいい？いくよ！ナイトループ！
Well, are you ready? Here we go! Night Loop!
相変わらず絵ばかり見ておかしくなる
Still staring at pictures and going crazy,
やりたくもないって言ってさ
saying I don't want to do this,
積み重ねてく明日に背を向け 色褪せた過去とやり合ってんだ
turning my back on piling-up tomorrows, fighting a faded past.
抑えつけるほどにかさ増していく劣等感 その場しのぎのガラクタもろもろ
The inferiority complex and makeshift junk piling up the more I suppress it—
こぼれる前に夜を染め上げなきゃ
I have to dye the night before it overflows.
できっこないポーズ決め込んで
Striking poses that can't be done,
満身創痍で詰め込んで
packing it all in while battered and bruised,
叩き終わったバブル一つ一つも飲み込めないくらい
so much that I can't even swallow each popped bubble one by one.
ほらくれてやるよ食えよ全部ちゃんと噛んで味わいながら
Look, I'll give it to you, eat it all, chewing and savoring it properly.
感想聞いてみてもいいですか
May I ask for your thoughts?
僕ら灰を背負ったままナイトループだ
We carry our ashes as we do the night loop,
そう 壊れるまで
yes, until we break.
運命をぎゅっとしたサイコロルールじゃ もう縛れないよ
With dice rules squeezing fate tight, we can no longer be bound.
正解すら間違っているんだそうだろ 誰も彼もバカみたい
Even the correct answers are wrong, aren't they? Everyone's like a fool.
痛いの飛んでいけ ナイトループだ
Pain, fly away! It's a night loop,
そう 上がれるまで
yes, until we can rise.
やいのやいのどうしようもないから
Making a fuss because there's nothing we can do,
もう語らないで あと少しで 絶望と希望の境界線 背伸びすれば届きそうだな
stop talking now, just a little more and the boundary of despair and hope—if I stretch on tiptoe, I might reach it.
うだうだうだ 脱線したい
Fidgeting, wanting to derail.
うわって声も漏らしちゃって 目逸らしちゃって
Letting out cries of "Whoa", looking away,
へこみ散らすまでがワンセット
getting thoroughly depressed is all part of the set.
やりきりアンダー 毎日がニューな己のバースデイ
Push through it, under—every day is my own new birthday.
諦めても諦めなくても僕を置いて進んでく時間
Whether I give up or not, time moves on, leaving me behind.
抜け出せないなら乗るしかないじゃん しゃあないなあ
If I can't escape, I have no choice but to ride along, oh well.
湧いてこうぜほらナイトループだ もう止まらないね
Boil up, hey, it's a night loop, it won't stop anymore!
変になったのどっちなんだかさっぱりわからないね
I have no idea which of us became strange.
明後日前で巻き戻って期待の延長戦
Rewinding to the day after tomorrow, an extended match of expectations—
1か8か3か夜か
one or eight, three or night,
最後に笑うためなら幾らだって泣いて抗おうか
if it's so I can laugh at the end, I'll cry as much as it takes and fight back.
元の自分が未来から手を振っている
My former self is waving from the future.
行こうぜ向こうの先へ ああ I'm happy
Let's go beyond yonder—ah, I'm happy.
まだ夜は明けない 燻るネオンサイン
The night still hasn't broken, smoldering neon signs—
不安掻き消そうぜ
let's blow away the anxiety!
まだ夢は覚めない 笑う疑問符
The dream still hasn't awakened, laughing question marks—
今打ち消そうぜ
let's erase them now!
僕ら灰を背負ったままナイトループだ
We carry our ashes as we do the night loop,
そう 壊れるまで
yes, until we break.
運命をぎゅっとしたサイコロルールじゃ もう縛れないよ
With dice rules squeezing fate tight, we can no longer be bound.
正解すら間違っているんだそうだろ 誰も彼もバカみたい
Even the correct answers are wrong, aren't they? Everyone's like a fool.
痛いの飛んでいけ ナイトループだ
Pain, fly away! It's a night loop,
そう 上がれるまで
yes, until we can rise.
やいのやいのどうしようもないから
Making a fuss because there's nothing we can do—
もう騙さないで
Don't trick me anymore
あと少しで
Just a little bit more
絶望と希望の境界線
The boundary line of despair and hope
背伸びすれば届きそうな称賛
Praise that seems within reach if I stretch
うだうだ
Moping around,
moaning and groaning,
うだうだ
complaining endlessly,
moping around...
脱線したい
I want to derail.
ループ
Loop
2018年から5年間 通り過ぎてきた たくさんの夜
For five years since 2018, I've passed through countless nights.
長かったような 短かったような
It felt so long, yet so short.
何度でも繰り返したいような 繰り返したい…
Something I'd want to repeat over and over again... want to repeat...
君はこのループから抜け出したい？
Do you want to escape from this loop?
君はこのループを抜け出すことを選んだんだね。
You chose to break out of this loop, didn't you.
そっか。
I see.
じゃあ、うちと6年目を始めよう！
Then, let's start year six together!
なんかワクワクしてきた。
I'm starting to get excited.
最後にもう1曲だけ、
Just one last song,
アンコール、聴いてね。
an encore, please listen.
シリウス。
Sirius.
ごめんね ありがとう 声に出して見ても
I'm sorry, thank you, even when I say it out loud,
届かない 戻らない あの日の僕らは
it doesn't reach, it won't return, we of that day
繋ぎ手繋いで 朝に怯えて震えていた
held hands tightly, trembling in fear of the morning.
失わないで、と 消えないで、と 願っても
Even wishing "Don't lose it," "Don't fade away,"
色褪せてゆく 記憶の破片 抱きしめ
clutching the fading fragments of memory,
眠るよ 「逢いたい」
I sleep. "I want to see you,"
ただ、願うほどに 目を閉じて
the more I simply wish, the more I close my eyes,
醒めないで 深い憂夢の中 いつかの君を探している
and in the deep, unawakening dream, I keep searching for you of someday.
僕はまだ あの夜を 独りで歩こう
I will still walk that night alone.
呼吸も 温度も 失した世界に
In a world that lost both breath and warmth,
約束は 今も 美しいままで
our promise remains as beautiful as ever,
夜空に咲いている 君の声だけ 聞こえないよ
blooming in the night sky. Only your voice, I cannot hear.
ここにいるのに 叫ぶのに 夜はまた隠してしまう
Even though I'm here, even though I shout, the night hides it away again
優しい嘘で 包んで どうかして
wrapped in a gentle lie, please somehow
またあした、とも 言えないいまは
right now, when I can't even say "See you tomorrow,"
彼方へとゆく 君を想うよ もう一度だけ 笑いかけて
I think of you heading into the distance. Just smile at me one more time,
きっとまた それだけで 僕は
surely, just that would be enough for me.
待っていた 季節が解けるように
As if the waiting season is thawing,
やがて 夜は明けるから
before long, the night will break,
動き出す 時が二人を遠く離れても
and time moves on, even if it separates us far apart,
心は繋げて
our hearts stay connected.
サヨナラは、まだ
"Goodbyes are still..."
こぼれた涙は
The spilled tears
君がゆく あの空を飾るよ
will adorn the sky where you go.
迷わないように輝いてて
Shine on so you won't lose your way.
いつまでも忘れない君を追うよ
I will chase after you, never forgetting.
明日も歌うよ
I'll sing tomorrow too,
明日を
sing of tomorrow.
愛しいと願うほどに
The more I yearn and wish for it,
僕らがまた巡り会う日まで
until the day we meet again,
おやすみ
goodnight.
相変わらずえばかりに手をおかしくなるやりくり持ってく
Still putting on airs, struggling with awkward management,
責任かげこわすに目を向け色あせた過去とやり合ってんだ
fencing with a faded past while turning a blind eye to responsibility.
抑えつけるほどにかさを増していく劣等感 その他諸々
An inferiority complex that grows the more you suppress it, and all the rest.
浸る前に夜を染め上げなくちゃ Flap...Phew!
We've got to dye the night before we drown in it! Flap... Phew!
敵じゃないほうで決め込んで
Deciding on the non-enemy side,
端からぽけ詰め込んで
stuffing our pockets from the edge,
叩き合ったらば増える一つ又一つ飲み込めないくらい
beating each other up makes them pile up one by one, more than we can swallow.
ほらくれてやるよ食えよ全部ちゃんと噛んで味わいながら
Here, I'll give it to you, eat it all up, chewing properly and savoring it.
感想聞いてみてもいいですか
Would it be okay to ask for your thoughts?
期待の飛んでいけないグループだ そうあがれるまで
We're a group that can't fly on expectations, until we can rise up like this.
やいのやいのどうしょうもないから もう語らないで
There's no point in all the fuss, so stop talking already.
あと少しで絶望と希望の境界線 背伸びすれば届きそうな超再生
Just a bit more to the boundary of despair and hope, super regeneration within reach if we stretch.
いつも応援してくれているミオファのみんな
To all the Miofa who always support me,